<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[External Knowledge Blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[Where tech knowledge ignites curiosity.]]></description><link>https://educationwithwork.wixsite.com/index/my-blog</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 10:43:35 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://educationwithwork.wixsite.com/index/blog-feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title><![CDATA[What are the Upcoming Cybersecurity Trends to Watch Out for in 2022?]]></title><description><![CDATA[In current approaches, cybersecurity domain is extremely ingenious. Now that we are ushering in new year, it’s important to keep track...]]></description><link>https://educationwithwork.wixsite.com/index/post/what-are-the-upcoming-cybersecurity-trends-to-watch-out-for-in-2022</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66e15800230b6fbaed2e0f24</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:47:07 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/9112846f96204977a0464974d2073fc3.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>educationwithwork</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In current approaches, cybersecurity domain is extremely ingenious. Now that we are ushering in new year, it’s important to keep track with the prevailing trends in cybersecurity that will reign in the technological age of tomorrow. The following are the key trends that are expected to make the biggest impact on the cyber world in the next year:</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><u><strong>Zero</strong></u><strong> Trust Architecture</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>With today’s cyber threats, engaging in conventional security does not seem practical, Hence the introduction of Zero Trust Architecture. The ‘Don’t trust, always verify’ approach helps organizations to minimize the risks around cyber threats.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>AI-Powered Security Solutions</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As for 2022, the incorporation of Artificial Intelligence inside the cybersecurity operations will improve. As with the use of AI based tools, anomalies can be spotted very quickly, potential risks can be predicted and incident responses provided within the shortest time possible.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong>Ransomware Resilience</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>There were widespread reports of ransomware increasing in frequency in the year of 2021 therefore causing the organizations to prepare for the worst. Through robust threat intelligence and efficient backup strategies, there will be an intense emphasis on ransomware preparedness all year round in 2022.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><u><strong>Cloud</strong></u><strong> Security Enhancements</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As cloud services are quickly being adopted, a fresh perspective in figuring out how to secure the cloud is required. While moving to the cloud, amongst the top concerns would be the protection of data, encryption and compliance in order to protect private data.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<ol>
  <li><p><u><strong>Security</strong></u><strong> In IoT Devices</strong></p></li>
</ol>
<p><br /></p>
<p>The increase in the use of interconnected devices and the Internet of Things (IoT) open up new vulnerabilities through device security. In 2022, IoT security policies, threat discovery and device authentication systems will gain more focus.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>As we prepare to face the cybercrime environment that is advanced in the year 2022, being alert and active is the best way to avoid risks. Incorporation of advances in technology, changing people’s attitudes towards the importance of cyber threats and implementing strong defense mechanism will leave a business at a better position than it was to threats.</p>
<p><br /></p>
<p>Lastly, the emerging cyber security challenges in the near future of 2022 look at protecting the digital resource with more preventive measures than reactive ones. Threats are timely; thus, it is necessary for individuals and organizations to remain vigilant in the ever-changing world and know how to embrace the trends. Let us go through this pain in order to get to a safe and progressive digital world!</p>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[How to Choose the Best Programming Language for Beginners]]></title><description><![CDATA[Are you looking to dip your toes into the world of programming but not sure where to start? With so many programming languages out there,...]]></description><link>https://educationwithwork.wixsite.com/index/post/how-to-choose-the-best-programming-language-for-beginners</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66e14fca608d1759c9eb3c5f</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:07:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/18c0e1_f6bc0f6af9384679ae30c02237c452f3~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_896,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>educationwithwork</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;"><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Are you looking to dip your toes into the world of programming but not sure where to start? With so many programming languages out there, it can be overwhelming to choose the best one for beginners. Don&apos;t worry, we&apos;ve got you covered! In this guide, we&apos;ll walk you through how to choose the best programming language as a beginner.</span></span></strong></p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/11062b_3bc0a742dcc54a698a440056823c715f~mv2.jpg/v1/fit/w_1000,h_1000,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<ol>
  <li><p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Consider Your Goals:
Before diving into a programming language, it&apos;s essential to consider your goals and what you want to achieve with coding. Are you interested in web development, mobile app development, data analysis, or something else? Different programming languages are better suited for specific tasks, so having a clear goal in mind will help you narrow down your options.</span></span></strong></p></li>
  <li><p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Ease of Learning:
As a beginner, you&apos;ll want to choose a programming language that is relatively easy to learn. Some languages have simpler syntax and concepts, making them more beginner-friendly. Languages like Python and JavaScript are known for their readability and ease of use, making them great choices for newcomers.</span></span></strong></p></li>
  <li><p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Community Support:
Having a robust community of developers can be incredibly beneficial, especially when you&apos;re just starting. A strong community means access to resources, tutorials, forums, and support when you get stuck. Look for programming languages with active and helpful communities to aid in your learning journey.</span></span></strong></p></li>
  <li><p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Versatility:
While it&apos;s essential to choose a language that aligns with your goals, opting for a versatile language can also be advantageous. Languages like Python and Java are widely used across various domains, giving you the flexibility to switch fields if needed. This versatility can open up more opportunities for you in the future.</span></span></strong></p></li>
  <li><p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Job Market Demand:
If your goal is to eventually land a job in the tech industry, it&apos;s worth considering the demand for specific programming languages in the job market. Research which languages are most sought after by employers in your desired field and factor that into your decision-making process.</span></span></strong></p></li>
  <li><p><strong><span style="color: #000000;"><span style="background-color: #FFFFFF;">Personal Interest:
Ultimately, the best programming language for you is one that aligns with your interests and passions. If you&apos;re genuinely excited about a particular language or enjoy working with it, you&apos;ll be more motivated to learn and improve your skills. Follow your interests and choose a language that sparks your curiosity.
In conclusion, there is no one-size-fits-all answer to the question of the best programming language for beginners. It ultimately depends on your goals, preferences, and aspirations. Take the time to research and explore different languages before settling on one. Remember, learning to code is a journey, so enjoy the process and embrace the challenges along the way. Happy coding!</span></span></strong></p></li>
</ol>]]></content:encoded></item><item><title><![CDATA[The Latest Trends in Cybersecurity for 2021]]></title><description><![CDATA[In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, cybersecurity remains a critical area of focus for businesses and individuals alike. As we...]]></description><link>https://educationwithwork.wixsite.com/index/post/the-latest-trends-in-cybersecurity-for-2021</link><guid isPermaLink="false">66e14fca608d1759c9eb3c5e</guid><pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:07:38 GMT</pubDate><enclosure url="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/18c0e1_b4b9bdee56724dbdb7c0c8e10d0cc50a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_896,al_c,q_80/file.png" length="0" type="image/png"/><dc:creator>educationwithwork</dc:creator><content:encoded><![CDATA[<p style="text-align: left;">In the ever-evolving landscape of technology, cybersecurity remains a critical area of focus for businesses and individuals alike. As we step into 2021, new trends are emerging in the cybersecurity realm to combat the increasingly sophisticated threats posed by cybercriminals. Let&apos;s delve into some of the latest trends shaping the cybersecurity landscape this year.</p>
<figure><img src="https://static.wixstatic.com/media/18c0e1_b4b9bdee56724dbdb7c0c8e10d0cc50a~mv2.png/v1/fit/w_1000,h_896,al_c,q_80/file.png"></figure>
<p style="text-align: left;">One of the prominent trends gaining traction in 2021 is the rise of zero trust security models. Traditionally, security measures have been perimeter-based, relying on the assumption that threats are external. However, the zero trust model operates on the principle of &quot;never trust, always verify.&quot; This approach entails verifying all users and devices attempting to connect to a network, regardless of their location. By implementing stringent identity verification protocols and continuously monitoring user behavior, organizations can enhance their security posture and mitigate the risk of insider threats.
Another key trend in cybersecurity for 2021 is the increased adoption of artificial intelligence (AI) and machine learning (ML) technologies. AI and ML are being leveraged to augment cybersecurity measures, enabling organizations to detect and respond to threats in real-time. These technologies can analyze vast amounts of data to identify patterns and anomalies that may indicate malicious activity. By incorporating AI-driven solutions into their security arsenal, businesses can proactively defend against cyber threats and minimize the impact of potential breaches.
Additionally, the proliferation of Internet of Things (IoT) devices has necessitated a renewed focus on IoT security in 2021. With an expanding network of interconnected devices, the attack surface for cyber threats has widened significantly. As such, securing IoT devices and networks has become a top priority for organizations looking to safeguard their sensitive data. Implementing robust encryption protocols, ensuring regular software updates, and implementing network segmentation are some of the strategies being employed to fortify IoT security in the current landscape.
Furthermore, the shift towards remote work arrangements in response to the global pandemic has underscored the importance of securing remote access and communication channels. Virtual private networks (VPNs), multi-factor authentication (MFA), and secure communication platforms have become indispensable tools for ensuring the confidentiality and integrity of data transmitted between remote employees and corporate networks. As remote work continues to be prevalent, organizations are investing in technologies that support secure remote access and collaboration to prevent unauthorized access and data breaches.
In conclusion, the cybersecurity trends for 2021 reflect the ongoing efforts to adapt to the evolving threat landscape and address new challenges posed by technological advancements. By embracing zero trust security models, leveraging AI and ML technologies, enhancing IoT security, and prioritizing secure remote access, organizations can bolster their defenses against cyber threats and safeguard their digital assets in the year ahead. Staying informed about the latest cybersecurity trends and proactively implementing robust security measures will be imperative in navigating the complex cybersecurity landscape of 2021 and beyond.</p>]]></content:encoded></item></channel></rss>